

MD. NISHAT HOSSAIN

Experienced | Skilled | Motivated

CONTACT INFORMATION



🎀 10/I, Naya Paltan, Dhaka.



+8801707061153



nishat.h45@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/nishat-hossain-07059079

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MS Word
- MS Excel
- MS PowerPoint
- **SPSS**
- E-Mail & Internet

EXPERTISE

- Sales and process Development
- **Trade Marketing**
- Marketing and activation
- Brand and demand planning
- **Channel Distribution Development**
- Project planning and evaluation
- Direct sales
- Resource capacity Development

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Highly self-motivated and organized outside Marketing, Sales and Trade marketing professional looking for the Mid level position where my extensive and diverse sales and Trade marketing experience and skills can positively impact sales revenue. 6 years of documented track record of sales development and maximizing sales through establishing strong Brand and trade marketing activity and customer relationships. A resilient nature together with a solid work ethic contribute to the achievement of demanding company goals.

WORK EXPERIENCES



RSPL GROUP

Position: Regional Manager

Duration: From 1st January, 2020 to Present.

- Designing zonal Strategy for growth and development of business for Detergent.
- Align Regional Strategy with National Strategy for maximum output.
- Sales planning and forecasting
- Monitoring and control of all sales operations and increasing profitability, business hygiene, business growth.
- Achievement of planned sales objectives through team management and development
- Periodic performance evaluation of team and giving feedback.
- Motivating sales team and prepare strategy for expanding distribution channel.



NESTLE Bangladesh Ltd.

Position: Territory Officer

Duration: From March, 2017 to December, 2019.

- Achieved 22.4% Organic Growth as Territory in 2018 based on 15.31%
- Achieved 16.44% organic growth of territory business based on 13.5% TGT in 2017.
- Win Highest Brand growth of Breakfast Cereal in 2017 at National Sales Conference.
- NIDO Yellow Jet initiator that was rolled nationally in Q3-2018
- National rollout project initiator of "Ekhane NESCAFE pawa jai" for tea bunk in 2018.
- NIM CHAMPION award for highest Growth 2019.
- Best Initiative Award for Pareto chart in 2019.

Robi Axiata Limited.

Position: Specialist, Trade Marketing

Duration: From November, 2014 to January, 2017.

- Got 4 out of 5 in 2015 PMS for extraordinary performance in each parameter.
- Highest sales event arrangement and highest new acquisition sales from events in 2015 KPI.
- Highest KPI achievement in region which is 129.39 out of 200.
- National 2nd best in activation trade campaign utilization.
- 2nd Best growth in SOV and Noticeability score in 2015 vs 2014 according to REI report December'15.
- National 2nd Best in 3G LUT event and revenue generation.
- National Best in 2G revenue achievement.
- 10.5% growth on trade loyalty and promotion in 2015 vs 2014.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Best Territory Officer Award in region for highest Business growth of 16%.
- Best Territory award for 22.4% Organic growth in 2018 in Region.
- Best Initiative award in Q-1 2018 for introducing Nescafe Overhead "Ekhane Nescafe Pawa jay".
- Win Best Initiative award for Project
 "NIDO Yellow Jet" rolling out nationally.
- MD's award for best project execution "Ekti Upazila Ekti RD".
- Win Top Gun Award as Best Regional Trade Marketing in Central Cluster Market for the period of Q1-Q3'2016.
- Best Initiative award 2019 for pareto chart.

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Team Player
- Organized & self-motivated.
- Good communication and interpersonal skill.
- Self-motivated and innovative.
- Creative and able to develop ideas.
- Like to take challenge.

LANGUAGES SKILL

 Highly proficient in listening, speaking, reading & writing in Bangla & English.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 22nd February, 1990.

Marital Status : Single Religion : Islam

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Permanent Address: Village: Fathepur, Upazila: Hathazari, District: Chittagong.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

♦ MBA in Management Information System 2013

Institution: University of Dhaka

Result: CGPA 3.38 (Out of 4.00)

BBA in Management Information System 2012

Institution: University of Dhaka

Result: CGPA 3.48 (Out of 4.00)

Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C) in Business Studies 2008

Institution: Chittagong University College

Result : GPA 5.00 (Out of 5.00)

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C) in Business Studies 2006

Institution: Chittagong University School

Result : GPA 4.88 (Out of 5.00)

TRAINING & WORKSHOP

- Sales Functional Competency workshop organized by NESTLE Bangladesh
 Ltd. (International Training).
- FIELD Sales Strategy organized by NESTLE Bangladesh Ltd.
- In Call Execution (ICE) organized by **NESTLE Bangladesh Ltd.**
- Stakeholder Management organized by SAPIEN and ROBI Axiata Ltd.
- Data Sales Training organized by ROBI Axiata Ltd.

REFERENCES

Syed Igbal Mahmud Hossain

Sales Director

Nestle Bangladesh Ltd.

227/A Ninakabbo, Dhaka.

Cell: +8801713257352

Email: Igbal.mahmud@bd.nestle.com

Mohammad Mehedi Hasan

Executive Vice President | Cluster Director Robi Axiata Limited, Robi Corporate Office. Nafi Tower, 53 Gulshan 1. Dhaka-1212.

Cell: +8801819210955

Email: hasan.mehedi@robi.com.bd